# 大家好 剛剛看了兄弟家的竹鼠哇
Hi everyone. We have just seen our brother's bamboo rats
# 發現旁邊有一口池溏哦
and then we found a pond nearby.
# 我們來釣一下這個魚 看看能不能釣得到
Let's see if we can catch any fish.
# 裡邊的全是那個草魚 很大的
These are grass carps, the very big ones.
# 來 魚鈎在這裡
Come! The hook is here.
# 哇 那裡有一條好大的
Wa! There's a very big one.
# 慢慢的遊過來啦 看看能不能勾到它
It's swimming slowly to our side. Let's see if we can catch it.
# 一條草魚喲
It's a grass carp,
# 好大的草魚
a big grass carp.
# 咬啦咬啦咬啦
It's biting! It's biting! It's biting!
# 哈哈哈 誒誒誒誒
Ho ho ho! Ek ek ek...ek!
# 嘿嘿
He he
# 別太用力拉 別太用力拉
Be gentle! Be gentle!
# 誒
Oy!?
# 哈哈哈
Hahaha
# 哎呀 大激動啦 還沒吃進去
Aiya. I was too excited. It has not even swallowed.
# 那個也在吃 那個也有吃
That one is eating too! That one is eating too!
# 你看 這個吃著菜葉子
See? It is eating the leaf.
# 讓它吃 吃進去
Let it eat, and swallow.
# 再來拉你
and then I will pull you out!
# 哈哈 今天晚上肯定有魚吃啦
Haha! I must have fish for dinner tonight.
# 還在吃 好像兩個人在搶哦
They are still eating. It seems that they are fighting over it.
# 好 看到沒有 還在吃
Right. Can you see? They are still eating.
# 去 繼續 繼續吃
Go! Go on! Eat it!
# 好像還沒咬到鈎一樣
It seems that it has not yet reached the hook.
# 它只是咬 菜葉子太大片啦
It is only biting, the leaf is too big.
# 先把 一直拉著走
First, it pulls the along the way.
# 輕輕一口悶了就成了哇
Just a small bit is enough!
# 菜葉子被吃完啦
The leaf has been eaten up.
# 這樣子都被它吃掉啦
How can I let it eat up my leaf?
# 氣死人啦
Damn it!
# 要把它勾起來
I put it onto the hook
# 讓它這樣它一口就可以吃得掉
so that the fish can eat it by just a simple bite.
# 誒誒 鈎到一條
Ey ey! I get one!
# 哎呀 哎 鈎到了
Aiyo! Ay! Got it!
# 小的 不知道甚麼魚
It's a small one. I don't know what kind of fish it is.
# 鯉魚
Li yu (Common carp)
# 鯽魚
Zei yue (untranslatable local carp)
# 哇 兄弟鈎到一條
Wa! My brother got one!
# 額 你來 你來 乾脆你來
Eh! Come on! Come! Catch it yourself.
# 別太大力
Be gentle!
# 等它
Wait!
# 不用太用力拉
Pull gently!
# 我們鈎了一條
We got one.
# 鯽魚
Ji yu
Zei yue
# 鯉魚喔
It's "li yue"
# 你看 這個太小啦
See? This is...too small.
# 我們不要 太小
We don't want it. It's too small.
# 把它放回去
Release it.
# 這個魚都不咬鈎啦
The fish are no longer biting the hook.
# 肯定是剛剛那條鯉魚哦 給它們通風報訊啦
The fish that we just released must have warned them,
# 說這個鈎不能咬
that the hook is dangerous.
# 現在咬都不咬啦
They don't even give a bite now.
# 知道我就不把那個魚放下去
Had I known that I wouldn't have released that fish.
# 先把它放到桶裡面裝著 然後再鈎
I should have kept it in the barrel first and catch other fish.
# 呃 現在要吃中午飯啦
Ah! Now it's time for lunch.
# 所以不鈎啦 下次我帶抽水機過來
So I am giving up. Next time I am coming with my draining machine.
# 這 這個魚太聰明啦
The fish, the fish are too clever,
# 比我還聰明
more clever than me.
# 那麼嫩 那麼嫩的葉子它們都不吃啦
The leaves, the leaves are so good but they are not eating.
# 下次來
I'll come again,
# 下次我帶我的裝備過來
with my gears next time.
# 抽水機
Draining machine!
# 好啦 今天的視頻到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 兄弟喊我 我回家吃飯啦
My brother is calling me back to have lunch.